<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EGI Docs – Configuration Database</title><link>/internal/configuration-database/</link><description>Recent content in Configuration Database on EGI Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/internal/configuration-database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Internal: Access</title><link>/internal/configuration-database/access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/internal/configuration-database/access/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The GOCDB can be accessed at &lt;a href="https://goc.egi.eu">https://goc.egi.eu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To access the web interface, users can:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>use EGI Check-in to &lt;a href="#using-institutional-account-via-egi-check-in">access the GOCDB with an institutional
account&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>use an &lt;a href="#using-an-x509-digital-certificate">X.509 digital certificate installed in the
browser&lt;/a>, delivered by
one of the recognised EU-Grid-PMA Certification Authorities ;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Users can access the system as soon as they are authenticated however they will
only be able to update information based on their roles.
More information about roles and associated permission is available in the
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/GOCDB/Input_System_User_Documentation#Users_and_roles">Users and
roles&lt;/a>
section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All roles applications need to be validated by parent roles or administrators.
Once this is done, you can access/modify relevant information according to the
role you have been granted. You can learn more on roles and user accounts by
reading the #Users and roles section of this documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="using-institutional-account-via-egi-check-in">Using institutional account via EGI Check-in&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In order to be able to access the GOCDB with their institutional account, users
need to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Have their Identity Provider (IdP) federated in EGI Check-in (via
&lt;a href="https://edugain.org/">eduGAIN&lt;/a> or directly) ;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have created an &lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/AAI_usage_guide">EGI Check-in
account&lt;/a> ;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Important&lt;/h4>
In the case the user cannot use an IdP compliant with &lt;a href="https://refeds.org/research-and-scholarship">REFEDS
R&amp;amp;S&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://refeds.org/sirtfi">REFEDS
Sirtfi&lt;/a>, the user will have to request joining a
specific group. Using a compliant IdP is the preferable solution.
&lt;/div>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>User should ask to join the &lt;a href="https://aai.egi.eu/registry/co_petitions/start/coef:41">GOCDB user
group&lt;/a> ;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The access request will be managed by the EGI Operations team.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="using-an-x509-digital-certificate">Using an X.509 digital certificate&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please note, GOCDB does not support single or double quotes in the certificate
Distinguished Name (DN).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This DN is rejected by GOCDB because of the single quote:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>/C=UK/O=STFC/OU=SomeOrgUnit/CN=David Mc'Donald
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>This is in accordance with &lt;a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1778">RFC1778&lt;/a> which
also disallows single quotes in all Relative Distinguished Name (RDN)
components, and the OGF Certificate Authority Working Group (CAOPS) who
strongly discourage any type of quote in a certificate DN as specified by their
Grid Certificate Profile document.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>