<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EGI Docs – Applications on Demand (AoD)</title><link>/users/applications-on-demand/</link><description>Recent content in Applications on Demand (AoD) on EGI Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/users/applications-on-demand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Users: Applications on Demand (AoD)</title><link>/users/applications-on-demand/aod/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/applications-on-demand/aod/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/services/applications-on-demand/">EGI Applications on Demand (AoD)
service&lt;/a> is EGI&amp;rsquo;s
response to the requirements of researchers who are interested in using
applications in a on-demand fashion together with the compute and
storage environment needed to compute and store data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can order and access the service through the &lt;a href="https://marketplace.egi.eu">EGI
Marketplace&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="service-description">Service Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The service combines compute and storage cloud with Application-development
and hosting frameworks to run custom scientific applications, and/or
to turn those into applications into online data analysis services that
can be accessed by scientists worldwide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The portfolio of applications is currently composed by a readily
available set of applications relevant to different scientific and
research areas. This portfolio is open to be extended thanks to the
contributions of users of the service. If you are interested in this,
please get in touch with us: support (at) egi.eu&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="intended-user-groups">Intended user groups&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The main target groups of this service are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Application developers who want to make their applications and tools
accessible in a scalable way for researchers internationally.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Algorithm developers (researchers) who want to run their own codes
at scale in a compute cloud.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The main target groups of the applications that are already hosted in this
service are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Researchers and innovators who want to run a specific scientific
application that is already available in the platform.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="scientific-applications">Scientific applications&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The scientific applications that are already available in this service are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://marketplace.egi.eu/applications-on-demand/68-chipster.html">Chipster&lt;/a>
a user-friendly analysis software for high-throughput data. It contains over 300
analysis tools for next generation sequencing (NGS), microarray, proteomics and
sequence data. The application is available through the Science Software on Demand
Service (SSoD). Instructions to run the application are available &lt;a href="https://docs.egi.eu/users/applications-on-demand/chipster/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://marketplace.egi.eu/applications-on-demand/58-namd.html">NAMD&lt;/a>
a parallel molecular dynamics code designed for high-performance simulation of
large bio-molecular systems. The application is available through the EC3 portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://marketplace.egi.eu/applications-on-demand/84-ecas.html">ECAS&lt;/a>
a complete environment enabling data analysis experiments from the ENES Climate
Analytics Service.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The service includes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cloud compute and storage &lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/public/ShowDocument?docid=2773">resources&lt;/a>
to host and scale up scientific applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Cloud access and application-hosting frameworks
(to run and to operate your own scientific application in the cloud environment):
that offer integrated development environments to port custom
applications with cloud resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://dashboard.appdb.egi.eu/vmops">VMOps dashboard&lt;/a>:
a graphical environment for the management of Virtual Machines (VM) in the
federated network of clouds that enable the Applications on Demand service.
User documentation is available &lt;a href="https://wiki.appdb.egi.eu/main:faq:what_is_the_vmops_dashboard">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://servproject.i3m.upv.es/ec3-ltos/index.php">Elastic Cloud Compute Cluster (EC3)&lt;/a>:
a portal that allows the creation of elastic virtual clusters in the cloud. Those clusters can then
host your scientific application either directly, or via Apache Mesos, Chronos, Kubernetes, Marathon,
&lt;a href="https://github.com/grycap/oscar">OSCAR&lt;/a> or SLURM.
Instructions for application developers are available
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/Applications_on_Demand_Service_-_information_for_developers#How_to_integrate_a_new_application_in_EC3">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://fgsg.ct.infn.it/egissod/web/ssod">Science Software on Demand (SSoD)&lt;/a>:
a programmable interface of a RESTful API Server to provide an easy access PaaS layer by leveraging
recent Web technologies. Instructions for application developers are available
&lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/Applications_on_Demand_Service_-_information_for_developers#How_to_integrate_a_new_application_in_the_FutureGateway_Science_Gateway">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="requirements-and-user-registration">Requirements and user registration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The service is open for any scientific software developer who needs a
scalable and user-friendly application execution and hosting environment
to offer data/compute intensive scientific applications online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Access &lt;strong>requires&lt;/strong> acceptance of &lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/public/ShowDocument?docid=2635">Acceptable Use Policy (AUP) and
Conditions of the 'EGI Applications on Demand
Service'&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Acknowledgment&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Users of the service are asked to provide appropriate acknowledgement of
the use in scientific publications. The following acknowledgement text
can be used for this purpose:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This work used the EGI Applications on Demand service, which is
co-funded by the EOSC-hub project (grant number 777536). The HNSciCloud
project (grant number 687614) is also sponsoring the service, allowing
users to access the HNSciCloud services pilot for limited scale usage
using the voucher schemes provided by the Exoscale contractor.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When requesting access to AoD users are guided through a lightweight
registration process. Members of the EGI support team will perform a
lightweight vetting process to validate the users' requests before
granting the access to the resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="service-grant">Service grant&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Once granted access, each user will have a grant with a pre-defined
quota of resources, which can be used to run the application of choice.
This grant includes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>up to 4 CPU cores,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 GB of RAM,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>100GB of block storage.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The grant to run applications is initially valid for 6 months and can be
extended/renewed upon request.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-can-you-access-the-service">How can you access the service?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Login to the &lt;a href="https://marketplace.egi.eu">EGI Marketplace&lt;/a> with the
EGI AAI Check-In service.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Setup a profile, including details about your affiliation and role
within a research institute/project/team.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate the marketplace top-menu and click on the category:
&lt;strong>Applications&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Applications on Demand&lt;/strong> service and submit an order
for one of the available applications.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the request is approved, run the requested application(s) as
described below.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Please check the &lt;a href="https://wiki.egi.eu/wiki/HowToAccessTheEGIMarketPlace">EGI Marketplace
guide&lt;/a> for
further details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Main scientific paper describing the service and status:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/document/3132">EGI Applications On Demand Service - Catering for the computational
needs of the long tail of
science&lt;/a> (May 2017).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2363/paper9.pdf">IWSG2017 Proceeding&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Presentations about the service:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://iwsg2017.psnc.pl/programme/">Slideset about the Applications on Demand (AoD) service introduced at IWSG 2017&lt;/a> (June 2017).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/blog/webinar-egi-applications-on-demand-service/">Webinar to introduce the Applicatios on Demand
(AoD)&lt;/a>
service to NGIs/USTs representatives, RI architects, resource
providers and researchers (June 2017).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://indico.egi.eu/indico/event/2875/session/35/contribution/89">Slideset about the status report of the platform at the EGI
Conference
2016&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://digitalinfrastructures.eu/content/serving-long-tail">Slideset about the status report of the EGI platform at the DI4R
Conference
2016&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://indico.egi.eu/indico/contributionDisplay.py?contribId=83&amp;amp;confId=2544">Overview of the EGI Infrastructure for serving the long
tail&lt;/a>
(EGI Community Forum, November 2015).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://indico.egi.eu/indico/contributionDisplay.py?contribId=124&amp;amp;confId=2544">Poster and animated
slides&lt;/a>
from Demo at EGI Community Forum, November 2015 (Winner of best demo
prize).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/document/2363">Slideset about the authentication and authorization model
adopted&lt;/a> (from Nov. 2015).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://documents.egi.eu/document/2358">Slideset about the concept of the EGI long-tail of science
platform&lt;/a> (from Nov. 2014).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Users: Chipster</title><link>/users/applications-on-demand/chipster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/applications-on-demand/chipster/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://chipster.csc.fi/">Chipster&lt;/a> is a user-friendly software for
analysing high-throughput data such as NGS and microarrays and provided
as part of EGI's AoD service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The software contains over 400 analysis tools and a large collection of
reference genomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users can save and share automatic analysis workflows, and visualize
data interactively using for example the built-in genome browser.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="egi-chipster">EGI Chipster&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Chipster testbed configured at &lt;a href="https://www.cesga.es/">CESGA&lt;/a>
offers:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>8 vCPU cores,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>32GB of RAM,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1TB of block storage in /data,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Software and tools are in available under the &lt;code>/cvmfs/tools_*&lt;/code>
partition,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chipster (v3.16.3).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For accessing this testbed you need to be a member of the &lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/services/applications-on-demand/">Applications
on Demand&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="createreview-a-temporary-account">Create/Review a temporary account&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You need to create a temporary account to access the Chipster server, by
default this account is valid for &lt;strong>one month&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="https://fgsg.egi.eu/egissod/web/ssod/chipster-accounts">Chipster entry in Science Software on Demand
Portal&lt;/a> and:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Show form&amp;quot;&lt;/em>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the account has expired, the Science Gateway will automatically
generate a new password for you.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To activate the new account, click on the &lt;em>&amp;quot;Execute&amp;quot;&lt;/em> button
to trigger the creation/update of the temporary account in the
Chipster testbed. This operation may takes a few minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can monitor the account creation by clicking in the
&lt;em>&amp;quot;Show&amp;quot;&lt;/em> button.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once your account is available, the web interface will show a link
to access the &lt;a href="http://chipster.aod.fedcloud.eu:8081/chipster.jnlp">Chipster
server&lt;/a> with the
new credentials.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../chipster.png" alt="Chipster in Science Software on Demand">&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Acknowledgment&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Please provide appropriate acknowledgement of the use in scientific
publications. You can use this The following acknowledgement text this
purpose:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This work used the EGI Applications on Demand service, which is
co-funded by the EOSC-hub project (grant number 777536)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Users: Exoscale vouchers</title><link>/users/applications-on-demand/exoscale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/users/applications-on-demand/exoscale/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In this section we describe how users can easily discover the &lt;a href="https://www.egi.eu/services/applications-on-demand/">EGI
Applications on Demand
(AoD)&lt;/a> service
published in the &lt;a href="https://marketplace.eosc-portal.eu/">EOSC portal
Marketplace&lt;/a> and submit a
service-order request to deploy an elastic virtual cluster on the
HNSciCloud pilot services. The virtual cluster will be deployed and
configured with the requested software packages using the &lt;a href="https://servproject.i3m.upv.es/ec3-ltos/">Elastic Cloud
Compute Cluster (EC3)&lt;/a> portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="submit-a-service-order-request-through-the-eosc-portal-marketplace">Submit a service-order request through the EOSC Portal Marketplace&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://marketplace.eosc-portal.eu/">EOSC Portal Marketplace&lt;/a> is a
single entry point where users can navigate the EOSC service catalogue,
discover a service of interest, get information about it, and place an
order in a few clicks by specifying the service requested along with the
quantity, quality and duration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the available services of the EOSC Marketplace are grouped in 8 main
categories and no authentication is required to browse and discover the
list of services published in the marketplace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exoscale vouchers can be used when selecting he Elastic Cloud Compute
Cluster (EC3) platform from the list of available services by submitting
a service-order request.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../ec3-eosc-marketplace.png" alt="The Elastic Cloud Compute Cluster (EC3) in the EOSC Portal Marketplace.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Placing orders in the EOSC Marketplace requires the user to
authenticate. There are two login options: use your personal academic
credentials or use EGI Check-in service. The first time you login into
the marketplace requires some extra information to be provided to
configure the marketplace account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two different service options are available for EC3:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../ec3-service-options.png" alt="The Elastic Cloud Compute Cluster (EC3) service options.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To deploy the virtual cluster on the HNSciCloud pilot services, select
the voucher option and click on &lt;em>Next&lt;/em> and provide additional
information for profiling the order (e.g. the motivation for requesting
the service).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users with an existing Exoscale voucher to redeem can provide the
voucherID during the submission request. Otherwise, a valid voucherID
will be provided once the order if processed and accepted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the service order is submitted, the marketplace will send a
notification via email. Users can at any time the status of their orders
through the user dashboard. This dashboard shows the history of service
order(s) submitted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../ec3-order-request.png" alt="Details of a service order request.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The service order request will be processed within 3 working days&lt;/strong>.
The user will be notified of the outcome of the evaluation via email.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="voucher-redemption">Voucher redemption&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In case the service order is accepted:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The user will be notified by the Marketplace with the instructions
to redeem the voucher (in case it was not provided), generate a
client and secret keys and access the Elastic Cloud Compute Cluster
(EC3) portal.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To redeem an Exoscale voucher, open the provided voucher link
included in the email sent by the Marketplace within a web browser.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A typical link looks
like:&lt;a href="https://portal.exoscale.com/register?coupon=XXXXXXX">https://portal.exoscale.com/register?coupon=XXXXXXX&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enter the email address and password you wish to use. Accept the
terms and hit sign up.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../exoscale-account-setup.png" alt="Accept the privacy license agreement and sign up.">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A validation email is sent. Check out your mailbox and click on the
verification link.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../exoscale-activation.png" alt="Activate the voucher clicking on the verification link.">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Choose &amp;ldquo;for team projects&amp;rdquo; and fill your details. Choose your
&amp;ldquo;Company or team name&amp;rdquo; and submit the form.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="access-to-the-exoscale-dashboard">Access to the Exoscale dashboard&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Access the &lt;a href="https://portal.exoscale.com/">Exoscale dashboard&lt;/a> and check
the tenant settings (click in the User profile on the left)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../exoscale-credentials.png" alt="Generate API and Secret Keys to access the Exoscale resources.">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="check-the-voucher-credit">Check the voucher credit&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Access the &lt;a href="https://portal.exoscale.com/">Exoscale dashboard&lt;/a>. The
voucher credit is shown in the top-right of the dashboard. In case
voucher credit is going to expire, a notification email will be sent by
the dashboard.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deploy-a-virtual-cluster-on-the-exoscale-commercial-resources">Deploy a virtual cluster on the Exoscale commercial resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Through a &amp;ldquo;job wizard&amp;rdquo; interface (see Figures below) the user can login
to the Elastic Cloud Compute Cluster (EC3) portal and configure the
virtual cluster with the related tools and applications to be deployed
on top of Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS). The cluster is composed by
a front node, where a batch job scheduler is running, and a number of
compute nodes. These compute nodes will be dynamically deployed and
provisioned to fit increasing load, and un-deployed when they are in
idle status. The installation and configuration of the cluster is
performed by means of the execution of Ansible receipts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../ec3-deployment.png" alt="Deployment of virtual clusters on Exoscale.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../ec3-wizard.png" alt="The EC3 job wizard to configuration the virtual cluster.">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgement-and-report-feedback">Acknowledgement and report feedback&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The user &lt;strong>MUST&lt;/strong> acknowledge the EOSC-hub and the HNSciCloud projects
in the scientific publications/presentations benefiting from the
service. The following acknowledgement statement can be used for this
purpose:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;quot;This work used the EGI Applications on Demand service, which is
co-funded by the EOSC-hub project (grant number 777536). The HNSciCloud
project (grant number 687614) is also sponsoring the service, allowing
users to access the HNSciCloud services pilot for limited scale usage
using the voucher scheme provided by Exoscale.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="report-feedback">Report feedback&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To report feedback on the Exoscale vouchers, please fill in the
following web form: &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/cVT7JRd4TFxZiYmQ8">https://forms.gle/cVT7JRd4TFxZiYmQ8&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>